JOO-HYUNG (DAVID) PARK

New York, NY • davidjhp11@gmail.com • (646) 812-2277

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am an avid problem-solver with 7+ years of experience growing a business unit and delivering quantitative finance solutions to Fortune 500 companies. With a proven track-record of creating new business opportunities, leading a large team, and bringing operational impact, I look forward to delivering success to the next emerging technology company.

MACHINE LEARNING AND DEEP LEARNING

Coursera - Deep Learning (5-course specialization by deeplearning.ai) 2019

Topics: Neural Networks, Hyperparameters, Bias/Variance, CNN, RNN, TensorFlow, Keras

Coursera - Machine Learning (11-week course by Stanford University) 2019

Topics: Supervised/Unsupervised learning, Regularization, Support Vector Machines

2019 **Udacity - Intro to Machine Learning** (10-week course by Udacity)

Topics: Naïve Bayes, Decision Trees, Random Forest, Ensembles, GridSearch, F1 score

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

PricewaterhouseCoopers LLP

New York, NY

Manager, Valuation and Consulting - Financial Instruments

2015-2018

As a valuation consultant, I advised corporate clients in estimating value of financial instruments such as stock options, convertible debts, and preferred equity that were privately placed with negotiated terms. As such, I designed and implemented customized models using statistical tools (i.e. Monte Carlo simulations, binomial lattice model), building on finance theories which include Black-Scholes option pricing framework.

- Generated \$2 million annual revenue with >50% margin by directing a team of 9 associates
- Created 3 new product lines and multiple marketing brochures to attract business, increasing annual revenue by 25%
- Sourced new business opportunities by leveraging internal and external networks, increasing annual revenue by 15%
- Led technical discussions with stakeholders on a daily basis, adjusting communication styles to fit the audience
- Directed a taskforce to build a credit rating model using logistic regression that achieved test set accuracy of 80%
- Assisted in growing a \$1 million revenue and 3-member team to a \$5 million revenue and 10-member team

Senior Associate, Valuation and Consulting - Financial Instruments

2013-2015

- Managed \$0.7 million annual revenue by delegating responsibilities and overseeing valuation process
- Presented at conferences, promoting team's capabilities on emerging modeling techniques and new lines of service
- Streamlined workflow and established in-office policies and guidelines, improving team productivity by 20%
- Coached 7 new graduates by designing classes and providing feedbacks, shaping them to be business professionals

Associate, Valuation and Consulting - Financial Instruments

2012-2013

- Composed 2 whitepapers that introduced new perspectives on a theoretical problem, igniting industry discussions
- Created 3 new EXCEL/Matlab valuation templates, which reduced modeling time by 30%; adopted by national practice

EDUCATION

Columbia University New York, NY

M.S. in Financial Engineering (CGPA: 4.08/4.00)

2010-2011

Honors: Gartland Fellowship (Top 5 students in Financial Engineering, Class of 2011)

University of Toronto Toronto, Canada

B.S. in Physics (with Mathematics and Psychology Minors; CGPA: **3.94**/4.00) James Loudon Gold Medal (Top 1 student of Physics, Class of 2010) Honors:

2006-2010

Provost's Scholar (Top 1% of all students, Class of 2010)

PUBLICATION & SKILLS

Publication Contributor: Derman and Miller. The Volatility Smile. 2016. Wiley Certification Completed all 3 levels of Chartered Financial Analyst (CFA) exams

Python (NumPy, Pandas, sci-kit-learn, Jupyter Notebook), Excel VBA, Matlab, Microsoft Office Suite **Tools**